VANESSA PACHECO

/www.linkedin.com/in/vanessa-pachecoi

Vanessapacheco.contact@gmail.con

6

(951) 496-2348



1227 N. Robin St. Apt D. Anaheim, CA 92801

EDUCATION

M.A. MASS COMMUNICATION, DIGITAL STRATEGY SPECIALIZATION

Graduation: Dec. 2022 University of Florida, Online

B.A. PUBLIC RELATIONS MINOR: MARKETING

Graduation: May 2020 California State University, Long Beach

A.A.FASHION MERCHANDISE/ MARKETING

Graduation: May 2018 Fullerton College

ORGANIZATIONS

AMERICAN MARKETING ASSOCIATION & AGENCY 241

AMA-Long Beach Jan. 2020 - May 2020

PUBLIC RELATIONS STUDENT SOCIETY OF AMERICA

PRSSA-Long Beach Aug. 2018 - May 2020

SKILLS

- AP Style/Copy Editing
- Research
- Written Communication
- Verbal Communication
- Strategic Planning
- Leadership/Collaboration
- Content Creation
- Time-Management
- Adaptability
- Bilingual
- Microsoft Suite
- Social Media Analytics
- Photography(Basic)
- Video Production(Basic)

ABOUT

I'm a furloughed part-time Disney cast member. Currently, I am pursuing a master's degree in mass communication with digital strategy specialization. I'm interested in opportunities where I can be of service and make a difference.

EXPERIENCE

FOOD SERVICE WORKER, COOK AND LEADER

Disneyland Resort / Feb 2015 - Current

- Demonstrated customer service by greeting guests and assessing orders.
- Worked independently and on a team to ensure the operation runs efficiently
- Prioritized tasks and delegated tasks to team members when necessary

PUBLIC RELATIONS/WEB COPYWRITER INTERN

P.O.P. Eco-Marketplace / May. 2020 - Current

- Developed an on-boarding guide for bringing in new vendors
- Wrote and planned website copy
- Researched and compiled information on potential vendors, influencers, and competition

PUBLIC RELATIONS INTERN

Fingerprint Communications / Feb. 2020 - May 2020

- Prepared presentations of press coverage for clients
- Coordinated gifting initiatives targeting influencers
- Communicated internally and externally to complete assigned tasks
- Researched and targeted media outlets and influencers

PUBLIC RELATIONS INTERN

Stanton & Company / Sept. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Researched potential influencers for various brands
- Drafted pitches and written materials for brand outreach & press opportunities
- Conducted media audits on clients
- Created media lists using Cision, Excel, and Google Sheets
- Prepared shipments to influencers and editors

SOCIAL MEDIA EDITOR

Inside Fullerton Magazine / Feb. 2018 - May 2018

- Utilized promotion techniques to increase readership and brand awareness
- Used social media to attract readers to stories online and in print
- Collaborated with the digital editor to set up a calendar to post and obtain photos and stories for posting.

PUBLIC RELATIONS LIAISON & SOCIAL MEDIA TEAM MEMBER

"Style Night" by Fashion at Fullerton College / Feb. 2017 - May 2017

- Increased recognition and exposure through strategies and tactics
- Communicated with VIP guests, photographers, journalists, models and designers via email, text messages and in-person.
- Instructed and managed a team, gave direction and supervised the production of the event.
- Spearheaded a promotion campaign for fashion event "Style Night"